Karina Gaulin

karinagaulin@gmail.com (720) 933-0539 Stafford CT. remote

FULL-STACK WEB DEVELOPER

GitHub LinkedIn Portfolio

Summary

I have been building beautiful and functional products for almost four years, including two in a professional environment. I began as an entirely self-taught learner, but to gain further mastery I enrolled in Bloc's Full Stack Web Development Program.

Now that I'm about to graduate from that program, I'm looking for a new opportunity to build gorgeous, usable web sites, in the Harford, CT area, the larger Boston, MA area, or remotely.

Skills

Front End: React.js, React Context, jQuery, HTML5, CSS3 Back End: Node.js, Express.js, MongoDB and PostgreSQL

Front and Back End: ES6 JavaScript, NPM, TDD with Mocha, Jasmine, and Karma, webpack and Browserify,

RESTful API Design

Additional Tools: Git, GitHub, Slack, Teamwork, Chrome Dev Tools

Experience

Dom & Tom, Inc.

New York, New York

November 2017 - January 2019

- FRONT-END WEB DEVELOPER
 Led the way for front-end development for several projects.
- Developed web applications with best practices and cutting edge skills including HTML5, CSS3, SASS/SCSS, FlexBox, JavaScript, ES5, GitHub, the command line, Slack.
- Created accessible websites with cross-browser compatibility.

Dom & Tom, Inc.

New York, New York

July 2017 - November 2017

FRONT-END WEB DEVELOPER INTERN

- Learned best practices and further developed skills including HTML5, CSS3, SASS/SCSS, FlexBox, JavaScript, ES5, GitHub, the command line, Slack.
- Learned how to work on a team and integrate my skills to fit what was needed for each project.

Stafford Library

Stafford,

Connecticut

LIBRARY ASSISTANT

November 2014 - November

2017

 Assisted patrons with the use of computers and software, lent and collected books, periodicals, videotapes, and other materials at circulation desks

Baby2Breast Breastfeeding Counselor Stafford, Connecticut May 2010,

November 2014

Recent Projects

Solution Spot | Github/Client | Github/Server: A full-stack application where solution-oriented people can share and discuss their ideas. Built with React.js, Context, Node.js, Express.js, JSX, CSS, Postgresql Binge Watch | GitHub: An app to help binge-watchers find information about their favorite show, as well as a list and information about similar shows. Built with jQuery, HTML5 and CSS3.

Education

BLOC

April 2019 - December 2019

- Learning industry best practices and practical software development standards with a focus on HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, jQuery, Node.js, React, Redux, and algorithms & data structures.
- Creating and deploying mobile-first, responsive applications while learning new languages and frameworks by collaborating several hours every week with a senior web developer.

Metropolitan State University of Denver **B.A. in Behavioral Studies**

September 2003 - June 2007